# ZHU, YUHAO

Email: y.zhu@ese.eur.nl � Website: www.zhuyuhao.com Erasmus School of Economics � Erasmus University Rotterdam

#### **PROFILE**

I am a Ph.D. candidate in finance at Erasmus University Rotterdam. I achieved my M.Phil. degree in Economics (research) at Tinbergen Institute, *cum laude*. My research focuses on asset pricing, behavioral finance and empirical corporate governance. My greatest strength is econometrics and programming. I am also strong in communication and presentation.

#### **EDUCATION**

Erasmus University Rotterdam, the Netherlands Philosophiæ Doctor (Ph.D.) Candidate in Finance, expected in August 2018 Promoter: Prof. Dr. Ingolf Dittmann; Co-promoter: Dr. Sjoerd van Bekkum	2015 to present
Tinbergen Institute & VU University Amsterdam, the Netherlands Master of Philosophy (M.Phil.) in Economics (research), <u>cum laude</u> Specialization: Finance	2013 to 2015
University of Groningen, the Netherlands BSc (Honors) in Economics and Business Economics	2011 to 2013
Fudan University, China BA in Economics	2009 to 2013

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

Asset Pricing, Behavioral Finance, Empirical Corporate Governance

#### TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer Languages	Python, Matlab
Statistical Software	STATA, Microsoft Excel (VBA)
Technical Skills	Calibration, Data analysis, Simulation, Visualization, Web crawler

# LANGUAGE SKILLS

Chinese (native), English (fluent), Japanese (basic), Dutch (basic)

#### AWARDS AND GRANTS

12th CAFM 2017 Outstanding Paper Award (USD 2,000)	2017
AFA Student Travel Grant	2017
M.Phil. Full Scholarship (EUR 23,280), Tinbergen Institute	2013 to 2015
Talent Scholarship (EUR 6,400), University of Groningen	2011 to 2013
First-class Scholarship, Fudan University	2011
Second-class Scholarship, Fudan University	2010

#### WORKING PAPERS

## "Wage gap and stock returns"

Joint work with Ingolf Dittmann and Maurizio Montone.

Presented at IFABS 2017 Ningbo, the IFABS Corporate Finance Conference at the University of Oxford\*, the Spanish Finance Association Meetings at Universitat Pompeu Fabra in Barcelona\*, the Behavioral Finance Working Group Conference at Queen Mary University of London\*, the Israel Behavioral Finance Conference at Tel Aviv University\*, and the Erasmus finance brown bag seminar series\*.

"The real costs of CEO compensation - the effect of behindness aversion of employees" Joint work with Ingolf Dittmann and Christoph Schneider.

Presented at 12th CAFM 2017 Seoul (outstanding paper award), DGF 2017 Ulm $^*$ , the Erasmus finance brown bag seminar series.

(\* stands for paper being presented by a co-author at the conference.)

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Instructor for Seminar "Advanced Corporate Finance: Corporate Governa	ance"
	2017 to 2018
Erasmus School of Economics, Erasmus University Rotterdam	
Guest Lecturer on Data Analysis with STATA	2017
Erasmus School of Economics, Erasmus University Rotterdam	
Thesis Supervisor for 1 Bachelor and 5 Master Students	2016 to 2017
Erasmus School of Economics, Erasmus University Rotterdam	
Instructor for Seminar "Advanced Corporate Finance: Corporate Governa	ance"
	2016 to 2017
Erasmus School of Economics, Erasmus University Rotterdam	
Thesis Supervisor for 14 Master Students	2015 to 2016
Erasmus School of Economics, Erasmus University Rotterdam	
Teaching Assistant for Course "Corporate Finance Theory"	2015
Tinbergen Institute	
Teaching Assistant for Course "Statistics"	2014
Tinbergen Institute	
PRESENTATIONS AT SEMINARS & CONFERENCES	
12th Conference on Asia-Pacific Financial Markets (CAFM) Seoul, Korea	2017
Korean Securities Association	
IFABS 2017 Conference Ningbo, China	2017
International Finance and Banking Society	
Tinbergen Institute Ph.D. Lunch Seminar	2016
Tinbergen Institute	
Erasmus Finance Brown Bag Seminar	2016
Erasmus University Rotterdam	
Tinbergen Institute Ph.D. Lunch Seminar	2016
Tinbergen Institute	

#### ADDENDUM: PAPER ABSTRACTS

## "Wage gap and stock returns"

(Ingolf Dittmann, Maurizio Montone, Yuhao Zhu)

We propose an asset pricing model in which the optimal wage gap between managers and workers increases with managerial skills. In a world with noise traders and short-sales constraints, we show that firms with lower wage gaps should trade at a premium, and the mispricing becomes even stronger if some investors exhibit inequality aversion. Using a unique data set of German firms, we provide strong support for the model's predictions. The results suggest that pay inequality within firms has important implications for asset prices.

# "The real costs of CEO compensation - the effect of behindness aversion of employees" (Ingolf Dittmann, Christoph Schneider, Yuhao Zhu)

Do employees who compare themselves to the CEO matter for executive compensation? Using German establishment-level wage data, we show that employee wages are increasing in CEO compensation. When CEO compensation increases 1%, the median employees wage increases by about 0.04%. Higher CEO compensation also increases the probability for the existence of employee stock ownership plans. We use a difference-indifference setting to provide causal evidence for the relationship. Our findings suggest that behindness aversion of employees is an important driver of wages and increases the costs of executive compensation significantly. We structurally estimate a principal-agent model with two agents (CEO, representative employee) to identify the behindness aversion parameters.